William A. Bernrieder Collection
University of Houston Libraries
- Franklin Roosevelt Visit, 1933-1980, (495 items) (Box 12-13, 16, Framed)
  - Parade Plans, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Participants, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Passes, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Photograph, undated (Box Framed)
  - Photographs, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Recap, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ship Channel Trip, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Alfred E. Jr., 1928-1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Publications, 1927-1981, (62 items) (Box 13-14, 18, Framed)
  This series was created from a box of publications which Bernrieder kept together. There are two sub-series: Miscellaneous and USS Houston. The publications in the Miscellaneous sub-series relate primarily to Houston history, the Port of Houston, and a book on Edmund W. Starling. Other smaller pamphlets and clippings will be found in other series.
  The USS Houston sub-series includes pamphlets on the USS Houston as well as books and other published materials which discuss the Asiatic Fleet and the U.S. Navy.
  - Miscellaneous--Brief History of the Texas Navies, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous--Houston and Cotton, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous--Oversize (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous--Port of Houston, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous--Ports of the Americas, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous--Starling of the White House, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous--Starling of the White House--Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous--The Texas Navy, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous-The Twenty-five Flags of Texas, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous--West Point Glee Club, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - USS Houston--The Builder, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - USS Houston--Cruiser Special, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - USS Houston--House Resolution 11681, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - USS Houston--Houston, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - USS Houston--Launching SSN-713 Houston, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - USS Houston--Launching SSN-713 Houston, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - USS Houston--Marine Engineering and Shipping Age, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - USS Houston--Presidential Cruise, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - USS Houston--Report on the USS Houston (Box Framed)
  - USS Houston--Shipyard Bulletin, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - USS Houston--Shipyard Bulletin, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - USS Houston--USS Houston: Ghost of the Java Coast, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - USS Houston--USS Houston: Ghost of the Java Coast, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- USS Texas, 1937-1980, (108 items) (Box 14, Folder 11-19)
  This small series relates to the USS Texas. Materials include clippings, correspondence, and publications which discuss the USS Texas. Most of the material deals with the addition of the USS Texas to the San Jacinto Battlefield.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Commission, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936-1978 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Program, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Publications, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Publications, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Publications, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous, 1917-1988, (365 items) (Box 15, Folder 1-23)
  These materials were not with other subject files and did not readily fall into available subject files. The majority of the materials in this series relate to a group of lithographs created by Judith Ann Saks of the Port of Houston, which were distributed throughout the country.
  - Brief for Naval Base, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Goodwill, 1978-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Hirsch, Maurice, 1975-1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Houston, Andrew Jackson, 1928-1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Houston Public Library, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photographs--Reagan, Ronald and Gerald Ford, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Port of Houston Lithographs--Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook Pages, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Ship Sponsoring, 1929-1959 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Texas Information, 1957-1980 (Box 15, Folder 23)